Register to The E. Robert Schmitz Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Photographs, Series III; .8' (2 boxes)
  - Laberge, Bernard, Maurice Ravel, Nina Koshetz, and Chaliapine "On board -?", 1928; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    See also: Royal Belgian Band
  - Ligne, Prince de
  - Loomis, Mrs.
  - Louis Ferdinand, Prince de Bavière, 1910; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    Inscribed
    See also: I.A. CORRESPONDENCE. Alphonse, Prince de Bavière
  - Mengelberg, Willem, 1927; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    Inscribed to E. Robert Schmitz, N.Y., photograph by Campbell Studios, N.Y.
    See also: Roussel, Albert
  - Milhaud, Darius, 1897-1974, and others (Box 13, Folder 8)
    ca. 1909. -- 2 items, Milhaud
    ca. 1915-1916. -- 1 item, Milhaud
    1930. -- 1 item, Milhaud with son, Daniel
    1930. -- 1 item, Milhaud with wife, Madeleine, and Daniel (Photograph by Lipnitzky, Paris)
    1930. -- 1 item, Milhaud (Inscribed to E. Robert Schmitz, photograph by Lipnitzky, Paris)
    ca. 1971. -- 1 item, Milhaud and Madeleine (At Mills College)
    no date. -- 1 item, Milhaud (photograph by Henri Manuel)
    no date. -- 4 items, Milhaud, Germaine Tailleferre, and 2 others
    no date. -- 1 item, Milhaud (Stamp on back: L.D. Bogue, Concert Management 130 West 42nd Street, New York)
    no date. -- 1 item, Milhaud (Photograph by Tipia - Max Eschig, 48, Rue de Rome, Paris)
    no date. -- 4 items, Milhaud
    no date. -- 1 item, Milhaud with Madeleine
    no date. -- 2 items, Milhaud with others (negatives)
  - Mirovitch, Alfred
  - Molinari, [Bernardino?]
  - Molnar, Ferenc
  - Monteux, Pierre, 1931 Aug. 29; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    Inscribed to E. Robert Schmitz and Germaine Schmitz, photograph by Gabriel Moulin Photo 153 Kearny St. S.F. Calif.
    See also: Saint-Saëns, Camille, and Schmitz, E. Robert
  - Onnou, Alphonse
  - Pawlowska, Vera, no date; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    As "Salome"
  - Pressler, Menahem (Max), no date; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Prévost, Captain Arthur, ca. 1929 Mar. 15; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    Both photographs inscribed - he was brother of 1st violin of Pro Arte Quartet
  - Prévost, Germain
  - Pro Arte Quartet, no date; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    Alphonse Onnou, Laurent Halleaux, Germain Prévost, Robert Haas
  - Prokofiev, Lina Llubera, with child, 1925; 1 item. (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Prokofiev, Lina Llubera, with 2 children, 1930 Feb.; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    Inscribed to Germaine Schmitz, Los Angeles, photograph by Studio Iris, Paris, negative laid in
  - Prokofiev, Sergey, and Lina Llubera, [1926]; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Ravel, Maurice (Box 13, Folder 11)
    no date. -- 1 item, Ravel "at birthplace (?)" [Ciboue, Basseo Pyrénées] inscribed to E. Robert Schmitz
    1928 Feb. 6. -- 2 items, Ravel with Lisa Roma? and John Barrymore (Studio of United Artists, Hollywood, California, negative laid in)
    1928 Feb. 7. -- 7 items, Ravel with Lisa Roma, Douglas Fairbanks, Mrs. Irish, Mrs. Boyce-Smith, and Violet Hart - Hollywood Bowl and the studio of United Artists, Hollywood California - "woman in nearly all pictures is singer who toured West with Ravel - singing his songs - Lisa Roma?? not sure - other women are L.A. Pro-Musica Executives" - negative laid in
    See also: Rubinstein, Artur
  - Roma, Lisa
  - Roth, Feri
  - Roth String Quartet
  - Roussel, Albert (Box 13, Folder 12)
    no date. -- 2 items, Roussel, inscribed to E. Robert Schmitz, Paris, negative laid in
    no date. -- 1 item, Roussel and Mengelberg
  - Royal Belgian Band and Arthur Prévost, Beckhard, Laberge, Ga-?, Prince de Ligne (Belgian Ambassador), Mayor Walker, Grover Whalen, ca. 1929 Mar. 15; 4 items. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    See also: Schmitz, Germaine
  - Rubinstein, Artur, Maurice Ravel, and Pawel Kochanski?, 1927; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    Negative laid in.
  - Saint-Saëns, Camille, and Pierre Monteux - Paris, 1913 Nov. 6; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Salzedo, Carlos, See: Schmitz, E. Robert, and Torpadie, Greta
  - Satie, Erik, no date; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    Portrait by Alfred Frueh
  - Schmitt, Florent, 1932; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    Inscribed to E. Robert Schmitz and Germaine Schmitz, photograph by Lipnitzki, Paris
  - Schmitz, E. Robert (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - E. Robert Schmitz and unidentified woman, Honolulu, 1927-1928 tour, ca. 1927-1928; 1 item.
    - E. Robert Schmitz, by Gene Lanner, Seattle, 1929; 1 item.
    - E. Robert Schmitz, photo of caricature by Esteban, 1930; 1 item.
    - E. Robert Schmitz, ink caricature by Loesch, 1930?; 1 item.
    - E. Robert Schmitz, Molinari, and Mirovitch (Inscribed by Molinari, photograph by Arrow Studio, Los Angeles), 1933; 1 item.
    - E. Robert Schmitz and "one of the classes at the E. Robert Schmitz Summer Session Duluth, Minn.", [1934]; 1 item.
    - E. Robert Schmitz and the Roth String Quartet Summer session, Greenwich, Conn. (Molnar, Antal, Roth, and Scholz), 1935; 1 item.
    - E. Robert Schmitz, pencil caricature by Valentin Shebaeff, [1936?]; 1 item.
    - E. Robert Schmitz and Summer Master Session, Golden Gate College, [1938?]; 1 item.
    - E. Robert Schmitz, Germaine Schmitz, Milhaud, and Monteux - Holy Names College, Oakland, California, after judging an E. Robert Schmitz summer session interpretation contest, [1940 or 1941?]; 1 item.
    - E. Robert Schmitz, photo of portrait by A. Pardinas, [1940 or 1941?]; 1 item.
    - E. Robert Schmitz and others, [ca. 1941?]; 1 item.
    - E. Robert Schmitz and 3 others, CBC program, [1946 or 1948?]; 1 item.
    - E. Robert Schmitz and others, summer session, photo by Mile High, Denver, 1947; 2 items.
    - E. Robert Schmitz and 3 others, North American Prize, [1948?]; 5 items.
    - E. Robert Schmitz and 2 others, Moulin Studios, San Francisco, ca. 1949 Jan. 6; 2 items.
  - Schmitz, E. Robert (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - E. Robert Schmitz, no date; 2 items.
      Negative laid in
    - E. Robert Schmitz - National Concert and Artists Corporation, no date; 3 items.
    - E. Robert Schmitz's hands, no date; 3 items.
    - E. Robert Schmitz, no date; 4 items.
    - E. Robert Schmitz, no date; 1 item.
    - E. Robert Schmitz - National Concert and Artists Corporation, no date; 1 item.
    - E. Robert Schmitz - National Concert and Artists Corporation, no date; 1 item.
    - E. Robert Schmitz, Milhaud?, and 4 others aboard a ship, negative, no date; 1 item.
    - E. Robert Schmitz and others, summer session, no date; 1 item.
    - E. Robert Schmitz and others, summer session, photo by Zuber & Damon, San Francisco, no date; 1 item.
    - E. Robert Schmitz, Darius Milhaud, and V. Golschmann "Paris - Théâtre des Champs Élysées 1ère des 'Études,'" photograph by Henri Nanhof?, no date; 1 item.
    - E. Robert Schmitz, Germaine Schmitz, Monteux and wife, Bliss, Salzedo, Barrère?, Mrs. Loomis, and others Reception for Monteux or d'Indy? - negative laid in, no date; 4 items.
    - E. Robert Schmitz and unidentified student(?) orchestra rehearsing a piano concerto, no date; 2 items.
    - E. Robert Schmitz with others, no date; 1 item.
      Originally near other items labelled "San Francisco teaching" in scrapbook no. 7
      Photograph by Lindevrii
  - Schmitz, Germaine (Mrs. E. Robert) and musicians of the Guides Belges, New York, 1929 Mar. 31; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 15)
    Inscription to Germaine Schmitz and signatures on back.
  - Scholz, Janos
  - Szigeti, Joseph
    See: Bartók, Béla
  - Tailleferre, Germaine
    See: Milhaud, Darius
  - Takano, Takeo, 1932 Feb.; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 16)
    Inscribed to E. Robert Schmitz, New York
  - Tansman, Alexandre (Box 13, Folder 16)
    1929 Sep. -- 1 item, inscribed, negative
    no date. -- 4 items, 4 copies
  - Teyte, Maggie, 1912 Mar. 4; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Thérémin, Léon, no date; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 16)
    With his Theremin
  - Toch, Ernst, 1887-1964 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    ca. 1928 Oct. 6. -- 1 item, Toch with his wife and daughter (enclosed with autograph letter signed, 1928 Oct. 6)
    no date. -- 5 items, Toch (negative laid in)
    See: I.A. CORRESPONDENCE
  - Torpadie, Greta (Box 13, Folder 18)
    193-?. -- 1 item, Torpadie and Hervor
    1924. -- 4 items, Torpadie with Carlos Salzedo, José Delaquerrière, Claudio Arrau, Dick Hammond, Arthur Bliss, and Hawley (at Carnegie Hall, after a performance of Bliss's "The Tempest" - photo by American Photo Service, New York - negative laid in)
  - Walker, Mayor [Al]
  - Whalen, Grover
  - Whithorne, Emerson, 1922 Oct.; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 19)
    One inscribed to E. Robert Schmitz, N.Y., the other by Arnold Genthe, N.Y.
  - Yasser, Joseph, no date; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Yoshido, Kyoko
    See: Bando, Mrs. Mitsumi
  - Unidentified negatives, one inscribed by Louis Ferdinand?, no date; 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Unidentified man - a singer? Paris, 1909 Feb.; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 20)
- Clippings, 1921-1989; Series IV; .4' (1 box)
  This series includes loose clippings. They are arranged chronologically. The clippings have been copied onto acid-free paper and the originals have been discarded. Cross-references appear for related material in other series. Many additional clippings were in 8 scrapbooks (1919-1940). A microfilm (box 23) and copyflo copy (boxes 24-28) were made of the scrapbooks. See series IX. SCRAPBOOKS.
  - 1921 Nov. 10, 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 1925, 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 1927 Sep. 23, 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 1928 Oct. 6, 2 items. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 1929 Jan.-Mar., 2 items. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 1931 June 14, 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 1932 Feb. 2, 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 1935 May-Oct., 2 items. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 1936 Feb.-Apr., 4 items. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 1937 Sep.-Dec., 4 items. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 1938 Feb.-Oct., 20 items. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - 1939 Apr.-Dec., 41 items. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - 1940 Feb.-Nov., 4 items. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - 1941 Mar. 27, 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - 1942 Apr.-Aug., 25 items. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - 1943 Jan.-Apr., 30 items. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - 1945-1946, 52 items. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    See also: VII. SCHMITZ SCHOOL FOR PIANO AND OTHER SCHOOLS. A.2. Summer sessions, and 5. Debussy Prize
  - 1947 Feb.-Dec., 8 items. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - 1948 Aug.-Dec., 12 items. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - 1949 Feb.-Oct., 15 items. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - 1950-1951, 35 items. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    See also: VI.C. WRITINGS BY SCHMITZ. Debussy book
  - 1953 Apr., 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - 1975 Mar., 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - 1989, 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - no date, 4 items. (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Programs and Publicity Material, 1918-1936; Series V; 1.7' (4 boxes)
  This series is divided into two subseries: A. Programs; and B. Publicity Material. Both subseries are arranged chronologically. A pencil note has been made on the many programs and publicity materials which were originally found with the disassembled scrapbooks.
  See also: IX. SCRAPBOOKS
  - Programs, V.A
    - 1918 Dec. 26, 1 item. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - 1919, 22 items. (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Membership card enclosed.
    - 1920, 14 items. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - 1921, 36 items. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - 1922, 25 items. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - 1923, 48 items. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - 1924, 25 items. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - 1925, 42 items. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - 1926, 53 items. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - 1927, 28 items. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - 1928, 43 items. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - 1929, 40 items. (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - 1930, 49 items. (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - 1931, 11 items. (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - 1932, 19 items. (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - 1933, 17 items. (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - 1934, 21 items. (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - 1935, 11 items. (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - 1936, 12 items. (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - 1937, 13 items. (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - 1938, 32 items. (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - 1939, 20 items. (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - 1940, 16 items. (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - 1941, 21 items. (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - 1942, 8 items. (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - 1943, 8 items. (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - 1944, 10 items. (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - 1945, 14 items. (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - 1946, 19 items. (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - 1947, 22 items. (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - 1948, 15 items. (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - 1949, 14 items. (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - 1950-1956, no date, 9 items. (Box 17, Folder 32)
      Includes a handwritten program for Colin O'More.
  - Publicity Material, V.B
    - Brochures, flyers, and press releases, 1919-1950; 250 items. (Box 17, Folder 33-37)
      Includes brochure for Antonia
    - Argentina (Box 18, Folder 38-41)
      Cover inscribed to Germaine Schmitz, Los Angeles, 1930
      See also: above programs for publicity material glued to scrapbook sheets; and IX. SCRAPBOOKS
- Writings by E. Robert Schmitz and Others, 1919-1950; Series VI; .8' (2 boxes)
  This series includes holograph, manuscript, typescript, and published materials. It is divided into four subseries: A. Lecture Recitals, Articles, Addresses, etc.; B. Scripts for Radio Lecture-Performances; C. Debussy Book; and D. Pro-Musica Quarterly. The first subseries is arranged alphabetically and the other subseries are arranged chronologically.
  - Lectures, Recitals, Articles, Addresses, etc., VI.A
    - "Ad[d]ress to the Key Club in Chicago", 1922 Apr. 11; 1 item; [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 19, Folder 1)
      Typescript with pencil additions
    - "Contemporary Modern Music", no date; 1 item; 2 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 19, Folder 1)
      Typescript with ink additions
    - "Debussy's Piano Style", no date; 1 item; 10 sheets; 26 cm. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - "The evolution of the musical instruments" (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - "Ritz Carlton New York", no year Feb. 29; 1 item; III sheets; 28 cm.
        Holograph in pencil
      - no date, 1 item; [2] sheets; 28 cm.
      - "Tuxedo", 1919 Sep. 26; 1 item; [1] sheet; 28 cm.
      - "The rights and duties of every individual in regard to modern music", no year Apr.-June; 1 item; 3 sheets; 28 cm.
        Typescript with pencil notes
      - "Process of evolution of the instrument" - Chicago, 1921 July 28; 1 item; [1] sheet; 22 cm.
      - "Étude sur l'incohérence et l'évolution - Le piano et celui de demain", no year July 1; 1 item; [2] sheets; 34 cm.
        2 programs, 2 clippings, and a Bartók brochure laid in
    - "France in Flux", 1944 June 26; 1 item; 11 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 19, Folder 3)
      Typescript (copy)
      Address by E. Robert Schmitz at the Institute of International Relations Mills College, California, broadcast over station K.L.X.
      Two copies
    - "Fundementals in Musical Interpretation", 1949 Aug.; 1 item; 6 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 19, Folder 4)
      Typescript
      Lecture
    - "The keys modes etc.", 1919-1921; 1 item; [9] sheets; 23-28 cm. (Box 19, Folder 5)
      Typescript and holograph in pencil and ink
      2 programs, one with pencil notes, laid in
    - "Music in an Awakened World", no date; 1 item; 4 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 19, Folder 6)
      "Carl Fischer" written in pencil on page 1
    - "Musical Accuracy", 1948 Aug. 27; 1 item; 7 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 19, Folder 7)
      Copy of typed letter from E. Robert Schmitz to H. Grady Harlam of the Southwestern Musician laid in
    - "Musical Accuracy", 1948 Aug. 25; 1 item; 7 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - "La Musique Française Moderne", no date; 1 item; [5] sheets; 29 cm. (Box 19, Folder 8)
      Typescript with pencil addidions
    - "La Musique Française Moderne", 1919 Mar.-June; 1 item; [3] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 19, Folder 8)
      Notes for lecture
    - "A New Viewpoint on Musical Contests", no date; 1 item; 6 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - "Psychology in Performance", no date; 1 item; 8 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - "Relation between fine arts and music", 1919-1921; 1 item; [4] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 19, Folder 10)
      Program with pencil notes laid in
    - "What Debussy and Ravel told me about their Piano Music", 1949 Aug. 17; 1 item; 8 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 19, Folder 11)
      For the convention of the Music Teachers' National Association - Synopsis of address to Piano Forum
    - "Why a Debussy Contest", no date; 2 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - "Why a Debussy Contest", no date; 2 items; 8 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - "Why a Debussy Contest", no date; 1 item; [4] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 19, Folder 11)
      Manuscript
      Holograph in ink
    - "Biographical notes - E. Robert Schmitz", no date; 1 item; 2 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - "Robert Schmitz Trips", no date; 2 items; 2 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 19, Folder 11)
      Typescript and copy
    - "Editings", no date; 1 item; 7 sheets; 24 cm. (Box 19, Folder 11)
      "Notes re Chopin Ballades..."
    - "Exams", 1948 June 21; 1 item; [2] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous jottings, no date; 2 items; [2] sheets; 22-36 cm. (Box 19, Folder 11)
      Holographs in ink and pencil
  - Scripts for Radio Lecture-Performances, VI.B
    - [Moussorgsky - Pictures at an Exhibition], 1937 May 8; 1 item; 6 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 19, Folder 12)
      Typescript with ink and pencil additions
      Columbia Broadcasting System, WABC, New York, Saturday, May 8, 1937, 6:00 to 6:30 P.M.
    - "All Ravel Program", 1938 May 25; lb: (Box 19, Folder 12)
      Typescript (copy) with pencil and red pencil additions
      Columbia Broadcasting System, WABC, New York, Wednesday, May 25, 1938, 5:00 to 5:30 P.M. EDST
      Typescript (copy)) and Continuity
    - [Moussorgsky - Pictures at an Exhibition], 1939 Feb. 16; 1 item; 5 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 19, Folder 12)
      Typescript with pencil and ink additions
      C.B.S.
      Portion of program with program notes by Frankenstein from a 1939 Jan. San Francisco Symphony concert laid in
  - Debussy Book, VI.C
    - The piano works of Claude Debussy. -- New York: Duell, Sloan and Pearce, c1950., Schmitz, E. Robert (Elie Robert), 1889-1949; 1 item; xix, 236 p.: ill.; 25 cm. (Box 20)
      Foreward by Virgil Thomson
      Edited and Designed by Merle Armitage
    - Typed letter with additions in pencil and ink (form letter) from E. Robert Schmitz to prospective publishers with proposal for Debussy book, 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 13)
      Includes publisher
    - Duell, Sloan and Pearce, 1950; 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 13)
      fall 1950 catalog
    - Negatives for Debussy book, no date; 4 items. (Box 20, Folder 13)
      illustrations
  - Pro-Musica Quarterly, VI.D
    - "FAMS Bulletin and Pro-Musica Quarterly: The Complete Run" (Box 20, Folder 14)
      Sheet prepared by Paula Elliott laid in. YUML's holdings are checked off
    - Franco-American Society Bulletin. -- Vol. II (Dec. 1923). -- New York: Franco-American Musical Society Incorporated, 1923, 1 volume; 23 cm. (Box 20, Folder 14)
      Irregular
      Continued by: Franco-American Society Quarterly Bulletin; and Pro-Musica Quarterly
      Library has 2 copies
    - Franco-American Musical Society Quarterly Bulletin. -- Vol.III (Mar. 1924) -- Vol. IV (Oct. 1924). -- New York: Franco-American Musical Society, 1923-1924, 2 volumes; 27 cm. (Box 20, Folder 15)
      Editor: Ely Jade [Germaine Schmitz]; Associate Editor, Greta Torpadie
      Continuation: Franco-American Society Bulletin
      Continued by: Pro-Musica Quarterly Library has 2 copies of Vol. IV (Oct. 1924)
      Library lacks: Vol. V (Dec. 1924); and [Vol. VI] (Mar. 1925)
    - Pro-Musica Quarterly. -- Vol. [I] (June 1925) -- Vol. VII, no. 3-4 (Mar.-June 1929). -- New York: Pro-Musica Incorporated, 1925-1929, 13 volumes; 27 cm. (Box 20, Folder 16-20)
      Editor: Ely Jade [Germaine Schmitz]; Associate editors, Greta Torpadie and Sigmund Klein
      Continuation: Franco-American Music Society Bulletin; and Franco-American Musical Society Quarterly Bulletin
      Library has 3 copies of Vol. III, no. 2 (Mar.-June 1926) and 2 copies of Vol. VI, no. 1 (Oct. 1927)
      Library lacks: Vol. III, no. 1 (Dec. 1925); Vol. V, no. 1 (Mar. 1927); and Vol. VIII, no. 1 (Oct. 1929)
- Schmitz School of Piano and Other Music Schools, 1920-1953; Series VII; .4' (1 box)
  This series is divided into two subseries: A. Schmitz School of Piano; and B. Other Schools. The items are arranged chronologically.
  - Schmitz School of Piano, VII.A
    - General Information, 1947-1950; 8 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      General correspondence, Statement of Purpose, course listings, announcements, list of representatives, and a poem dedicated to E. Robert Schmitz laid in
      See also: V. PROGRAMS AND PUBLICITY MATERIAL; and IV. CLIPPINGS
    - Summer Sessions, 1943-1950; 32 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      Includes course listings, repertoire, concert schedule, expenses, chart of students course of study, tuition, etc., an examination, and clippings
      See also: I.A. CORRESPONDENCE - California. Department of Education..., Mills College, Murray, Willie, and San Francisco State College; V. PROGRAMS AND PUBLICITY MATERIAL; and IV. CLIPPINGS
    - Trust Fund, 1947-1950; 40 items. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      Includes agreements, minutes, ballot sheets, IRS material, list of contributors and beneficiaries, memorandums, and lists of trustees
      See also: I.A. CORRESPONDENCE - Browne, Walter and Ione; Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague; English, Harold; Fiset, Gene; Geiger, Mrs. L. Porter; Havemeyer, Mary; and Henderson, Dorothy; and VIII. FINANCIAL AND LEGAL MATERIAL - Internal Revenue Service
    - North American Prize, 1946-1948; 40 items. (Box 21, Folder 4)
      Includes announcements, clippings, lists of applicants and finalists, a flyer, application blanks, repertoire lists, suggestion list, and grading sheets
      See also: I.A. CORRESPONDENCE - American Society of Composers, Authors, and Publishers; Bernstein, Leonard; Braille Musician; Browning, Mortimer; Carl Fischer, Inc.; Cassell, Marion; Coulthard, Jean Adams; Curtis Institute of Music; Del Purves, Miss; The Etude; Fiset, Gene; Foreign & International Book Company, Inc.; Greene, Gloria; Heidelberg, Jack; Henderson, Dorothy C.; Kahn, Erminie; Newton, Mrs. Quigg; Nordoff, Paul; Pflugfelder, Eleanor; Phillips, Harrison; Rudhyar, Dane; Spindler, Mariam; Stevens, Halsey; Talma, Louise; University of California; and Wulsin, Eugene; and V. PROGRAMS AND PUBLICITY MATERIAL
    - Debussy Prize, 1945-1946; 39 items. (Box 21, Folder 5)
      Includes announcements, postal receipts, clipping, notes, questionaires, expenses, invitation, list of audition dates and juries, seating for dinner, lists of contestants and programs, contest results, application blank, and brochure
      See also: I.A. CORRESPONDENCE - Bertrand, Raoul; Bonnet, Henri; and Henderson, Dorothy C.
  - Other Schools, VII.B
    - Cornish School, 1921 Apr.-Sep.; 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 6)
      Contract and financial statement
    - Lamont-Rinquest Schools, 1928 Aug. 16; 4 items. (Box 21, Folder 6)
      Financial statements
    - Seymour School of Music, 1920-1921; 23 items. (Box 21, Folder 6)
      Loose sheets with pencil and ink jottings about teachers, income, and expenses
    - Lessons in Chicago and Madison, 1921-1923; 7 items. (Box 21, Folder 6)
      Typescript and holograph in pencil sheets with expenses and income
      See also: I.A. CORRESPONDENCE under the name of the manager or name of company for box office and royalty statements, receipts, and contracts and agreements; and VII. SCHMITZ SCHOOL OF PIANO AND OTHER MUSIC SCHOOLS for financial and legal items
- Financial and Legal Material, 1917-1950; Series VIII; .4' (1 box)
  This series is divided into two subseries: A. Financial Items; and B. Legal Items. The items are arranged chronologically within each subseries.
  - Financial Items, VIII.A
    - Financial record by season, 1 item; [26] sheets; 31 cm. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      Typescript with manuscript ink additions